Guide to the Kenneth L. Turk papers, 1951-1985.
Turk, Kenneth L. papers, 1951-1985.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kenneth L. Turk papers, 1951-1985.
21-14-2116
Kenneth L. (Kenneth Leroy) Turk, 1908-
14 cubic ft.
Lecture notes, reports, consultation and advisory papers, and a manuscript.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lecture notes, reports, and consultation and advisory papers prepared by Kenneth L. Turk. Includes material pertaining to the Rockefeller Foundation and several food and agricultural organizations, and agricultural programs in England, Asia, Hawaii, Philippines, Brazil, Indonesia, Mexico, India, Guatemala, Columbia, Chile, and the West Indies. Also, "Flashbacks: Selected Travel Experiences of Bernice and Kenneth Turk."
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Animal Science.
Cornell University M.S. 1931, Ph.D. 1934
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Lecture notes, reports, and consultation and advisory papers prepared by Kenneth L. Turk. Includes material pertaining to the Rockefeller Foundation and several food and agricultural organizations, and agricultural programs in England, Asia, Hawaii, Philippines, Brazil, Indonesia, Mexico, India, Guatemala, Columbia, Chile, and the West Indies. Also, "Flashbacks: Selected Travel Experiences of Bernice and Kenneth Turk."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Turk, Kenneth L. (Kenneth Leroy), 1908-; Rockefeller Foundation.
Subjects:
Agricultural productivity.; Agriculture--Study and teaching.
Places:
Asia.; Brazil.; Chile.; Colombia.; England.; Guatemala.; Hawaii.; India.; Indonesia.; Mexico.; Philippines.; West Indies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Lecture notes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Notes for class taught. A.H. 50, Dairy Cattle, 1962 (Box 1)
- Series of articles on livestock in Europe of first sabbatical leave, 1951 (Box 1)
- Report on Dairy Conference, Thurgarton, England, 1951 (Box 1)
- Series of articles on livestock production in Asia, 1956 (Box 1)
- Council on Higher Education in the American Republic (Box 1)
- International program in Agriculture, University of Hawaii (Box 1)
- Latin American Science Board, National Academy of Sciences Communications
  - Communications (Box 2)
  - Reports (Box 2)
  - Workshop on scientific and technical cooperation, U.S.-Philippines (Box 2)
- USAID Brazil Binational Planning Team, 1970 (Box 3)
- USAID MUCIA Educational Program in Indonesia, 1974 (Box 3)
- Asian Development Bank: Evaluation of Educational Program of Malaysian Agricultural University, 1972 (Box 3)
- Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO)
  - Evaluation of Animal Husbandry Education in Mexico, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Evaluation of IRI Research Institute's Programs in Brazil, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Observation of Livestock Production Programs in India, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Technical Advisory Committee, Nutrition Institute for Central American and Panama, Guatemala (Box 4)
- Rockefeller Foundation
  - Correspondence and reports re: Service on Board of Consultants, R.F., Programs in Mexico, Colombia, and Chile, 1956-1962 (Box 6)
  - Diaries of consulting assignments (Box 6)
  - Review Team for CIAT, Colombia, on Animal Research Program, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Reports and diaries re: Colombia and Mexico (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous reports (Box 7)
- U.S.-U.S.S.R. Joint Commission on Scientific and Technical Cooperation, 1972
  - Communications (Box 8)
  - General Information (Box 8)
  - Reports (Box 8)
- Inter-American Development Bank Special Committee re: Faculty of Agriculture, University of the West Indies, Trinidad (Box 8)
- Program - Dedication, Turk Seminar Room, 1986 (Box 8)
- Personal materials (Box 9)
- Correspondence after retirement (Box 9)
- ADSA (Box 10)
- Instruction (Box 10)
- Prov. registration (Box 10)
- Savage (Box 10)
- Morrison (Box 10)
- Mrs. Morrison (Box 10)
- Miscellany (Box 10)
- Correspondence
  - Administration - Roberts Hall (Box 11)
  - Foreign countries (Box 11)
  - Los Banos - Philippines (Box 11)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 11)
  - Breed Assns. (Box 11)
  - G.L.F. (Box 11)
  - Misc. departmental (Box 11)
- Livestock Advisory Council (Box 12)
- McDonald Farms (Box 12)
- Regional Res. Projects (Box 13)
- Int. Agr. Dev. (Box 13)
- Res. contracts (Box 13)
- Consultancies
  - Ford Foundation - Sudan Project I, Organization and Administration of Agricultural Research, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Ford Foundation - Sudan Project II, International Workshop on Agricultural Research and Development, 1976 (Box 14)
  - AID/IADS, Agricultural Research Capabilities in the Sudan, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Evaluation of AID/World Bank Western Sudan Agricultural Research Project, 1982 (Box 14)
  - AID/IADS Report on Agricultural Research and Extension, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Evaluation of graduate training program, CATIE, Costa Rica (AID project), 1985 (Box 14)
  - Asian Development Bank (Box 14)